OMARI BOTA IAN MOGAKA

Box Address: 190-40501 IKONGE.

Mobile: +254 740037633 / 716871628

E-Mail: omarbotah@gmail.com

PERSONAL INFORMATION	
Date of birth:	1 St Feb 1997
Sex:	Male
Nationality:	Kenyan
Marital Status:	Single
PERSONAL SUMMARY	

I'm a self-motivated, hardworking Industrial Chemistry professional who is self-driven and ready to learn. I uphold Discipline, order in all areas with respect as key. I am self driven, with skills in good manufacturing practices, research and production fields and in areas of food technology and food safety and other many more chemistry skills.

I am organized and can multitask where need be to beat deadlines and do my work on time, and I look forward to utilize my strengths and inter-personal skills, excel and contribute towards the organization's growth and developments, and also further my knowledge.

SKILLS

Good Manufacturing Practices

Research and strategic planning

Industrial Manufacturing Processes

Food Technology

UV/Vis, FTIR, AAS, HPLC and other Instrumental Operation

Quality Assurance and Control

Analytical Chemistry

Computer packages, Word, Excel, PPT

Leadership

Public Speaking

Laboratory skills

CAREER OBJECTIVE

To obtain a challenging duty in a high quality environment where my existing skills, personal ability, and a commitment to professionalism will add value to organizational operations, and allow for continued academic, personal and professional growth commensurate with achievements.

To meet any institutional goals, targets and give the best of my knowledge and ability.

To stretch my Education base to fit constantly changing trends in technology for better output now

and in future.

WORK EXPERIENCE

SEPTEMBER 2019 TO FEB 2020

INTERN DAWA PHARMACEUTICALS LIMITED

TASKS

Raw Materials and pharmaceutical products sampling

Raw Materials and pharmaceutical products analysis

HPLC, UV/Vis, FTIR, Polarimeter and analytical instruments operations and maintenance

Calibration of balances

Lab maintenance

Production Quality Assurance

Warehousing and Final Goods Store operations.

MAY 2019 TO JULY 2019

ATTACHEE

MINISTRY OF PETROLEUM AND MINING

GEOLOGICAL DEPARTMENT

TASKS

Geochemistry Lab Maintenance

XRD Operation

UV/Vis Operation

AAS operation

Assay lab Maintenance

Geological lapidary operations

Pulveriser Operation

JULY 2018 TOAUGUST 2018

INTERNAL BASED ATTACHMENT

THE TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY OF

KENYA SCHOOL LABS

TASKS

Laboratories Maintenance Spectrphotometric analysis

Instrumental Analysis: Using The UV/Vis, FTIR, HPLC

EDUCATIONAL BACKGROUND	
2015 to 2019	BACHELOR OF TECHNOLOGY IN INDUSTRIAL AND APPLIED CHEMISTRY.
	School of physical sciences and technology
	Department of chemical science and technology
	Technical University of Kenya.
2014- 2015	CERTIFICATE IN GERMAN LANGUAGE
	Goethe Instut Nairobi
	B1 level
2011-2014:	KENYA CERTIFICATE OF SECONDARY EDUCATION
	Kisii School
	Mean Grade-A-
2003-2010	KENYA CERTIFICATE OF PRIMARY EDUCATION.
	Sakagwa Primary School
	Mean Grade: A
INTERESTED IN:	
Socializing	
Reading	
Reading	
Research on Climate Change and Inc	lustrial Research

REFEREES

Dr. Geoffrey Otieno

Chairman

Department of Chemical Science and Technology

The Technical University of Kenya.

Chairman-dcst@tukenya.ac.ke.

Mobile: 0700331903

Dr. Patrick Shem

Attachment coordinator,

Department of Chemical Science and Technology

Technical University of Kenya,

Mobile: 0703590258

Mr. Wilfred Omanwa

Geological Department

Mobile: 0705113931